just imagine that Russia Russia reached
вот представьте что Россия Россия дошла
Poland here are Russian troops standing
до Польши вот российские войска стоят
at the Polish
под польской
border this will be a conflict with NATO I
границей это будет конфликт с НАТО я
thought that this would not happen I think there will be a
думал что такого не будет я думаю будет
demilitarized zone, that
демилитаризированная зона такая то
is, a buffer zone, be it called
есть буферная зона будь она называется
there country 404 Ukraine there I don't know
там страна 404 Украина там я не знаю
Bessarabia there whatever you like Hungary there
Бесарабия там как угодно Угорщина там
can be called anything but a direct
что угодно может называться но прямой
border between respectively NATO
границы между соответственно НАТО
let's say well specifically Poland and
допустим ну вот конкретно Польшей и
Russia I think there will not be well this is my
Россией я думаю не будет ну это моё
opinion cool do you want me to tell you a
мнение прикольно хотите я вам открою
secret
секрет
yes of course Russia has a border with
да конечно у России есть граница с
Poland
Польшей
hello
здравствуйте
hello I am from the city of Khmelnitsky and
здравствуйте я из города Хмельницкий а
where are you from
вы откуда
yes Moscow region
да Подмосковье
what are you talking about
о чём общаетесь
just came in you can say the first
только зашёл вы можно сказать первый
interlocutor is super then I will now give you a
собеседник супер то я сейчас вам
chat roulette it turns out you are
чат-рулеточку это вы получается в чат
still a virgin in the chat roulette and have not yet
рулетке ещё девственник да ещё не
communicated with anyone no no no for today for
общались ни с кем ненене на сегодня на
today still and still not dirty got it
сегодня ещё да ещё не пачканный понял
now we will dirty you yes let's
сейчас мы вас испачкаем да давайте
give a
давайте
question like this look how Russia
вопрос такой смотрите как Россия
plans to win against NATO if it does not
планирует выиграть у НАТО если она не
strike NATO territory well
наносит удары по территории НАТО
this is supposed to be a cold war
ну это же предполагается холодная война
hot phases, respectively, wars with NATO,
горячие фазы соответственно войны с НАТО
back in the seventies they say that it was
ещё там в семидесятых годах говорят что
developed that all these
было разработано о том что все эти
nuclear strikes in a five-minute moment,
ядерные удары в пятиминутный моменте
once-once and in the dams, therefore there will be no hot phase,
раз-раз и в дамках поэтому горячей фазы
therefore this is Bryadsko not a weapon,
не будет поэтому это брядско не оружием
that NATO has, that Russia has, this is all for
что у НАТО что у России это так всё для
No, well, how Bryadskoe no, look at NATO
Не ну как Брядское нет смотри на НАТО
strikes on the territory of Russia, so
наносит удары по территории России так
on Tatarstan, on Nizhny Novgorod,
вот по Татарстану по Нижнему Новгороду
drones with what weapons, drones
беспило каким оружием по беспилотниками
no, well, we are talking about nuclear weapons,
нет ну мы же про ядерное оружие говорим
not but why
не а почему
nuclear who said I did not say anything about the nuclear word
ядерное кто сказал я про ядерное слово
I said why, look, well,
не говорил я сказал почему смотри ну
now not for half a crucian, so for
сейчас не на полкарасика так на
half a crucian, that's how it will be, well, wait, come on,
полкарасика так оно и будет ну подожди
Russia is fighting with NATO or with
давай так россия воюет с НАТО или с
Ukraine,
Украиной
uh, with Ukraine, and Ukraine is a testing ground,
ээ с Украиной а Украина - это полигон
come on, who is Russia fighting at the testing ground?
давай так с кем воюет россия на полигоне
Ukraine
Украина
started fighting with Ukraine, yes, and now it
начинала воевать с Украиной да а сейчас
is fighting now, and now, accordingly,
воюет сейчас а сейчас соответственно
Ukraine is a testing ground for a war between
Украина является полигоном войны между
NATO and, accordingly, Russia, that's it, no,
НАТО и соответственно Россией всё вот
no, that is, NATO and Russia are fighting
вот нет нет да то есть воюет НАТО и
no, no, I'm wrong, you are right
нет нет я же неправильно вы Вы правильно
incorrectly I said I said
неправильно я же сказал я же сказал
differently that in the beginning Ukraine started to
по-другому что в начале Украина начинала
fight with Russia right yes and now
воевать с Россией правильно да а сейчас
who is fighting with whom after which Ukraine with
кто с кем вое о после чего Украина
hands so to speak with NATO weapons is fighting on the
руками так сказать оружием НАТО воюет на
training ground which is called RO Ukraine
полигоне который называетсяРО Украина
because now that territory
потому что сейчас то та территория
which is called Ukraine yes it is a
которая называется Украина да это
training ground so yes then with whom with whom
полигон так так да то с кем с кем
let's so with whom Russia is fighting now
давайте так с кем воюет Россия сейчас
with Ukraine but with weapons and instructors
с Украиной но оружием и инструкторами
accordingly NATO that is NATO is fighting
соответственно НАТО то есть НАТО воюет
against Russia
против России
everywhere there are some but here there are no such
везде есть какие-то но здесь нет таких
direct answers and direct questions
прямых ответов и прямых вопросов к
unfortunately as Putin Medvedev says that
сожалению как Путин Медведев говорит что
NATO is fighting against Russia yes Putin
НАТО воюет против России да Путин
says that and what do you think what can they
говорит то а вы как считаете чего могут
say you can also say but that's
говорить вы тоже могут что говорить но
not the point the point is that what
дело же не в этом дело в том что что
is in fact in fact look do you
есть по факту по факту смотрите вы
think Crimea is Russia well there are
считаете Крым - это Россия
people walking there with Russian Yes yes
ну там ходят люди с российскими Да да
look yes look NATO missiles
вот смотри да смотри натовские ракеты
British British American these and
британские британские американские эти и
French yes they fly over the territory of
французские да прилетают по территории
Crimea yes that is NATO is striking the
Крыма да то есть НАТО наносит удары по
territory of the Russian Federation
территории Российской Федерации
NATO reconnaissance planes are flying over the
натовские самолёты разведчики летают над
Black Sea guiding them to targets yes like
Чёрным морем наводят на цели да как
Russia  NATO responds with
Россия отвечает НАТО
strikes on Kyiv,
ну ударами по Киеву
so what does NATO have to do with it? It's
так а НАТО при чём тут на НАТО от этого
neither cold nor hot, they have a testing ground,
не холодно не жарко это у них полигон
Ukraine, you said it's a testing ground, you said NATO,
украина ж вы это ж полигон вы сказали
what's the difference? Strikes on Kyiv,
нато какая разница удары по Киеву
they show what weapons
они же показывают какое есть оружие у
some have, these show what weapons, that
одних эти показывают какое оружие то
is, I'm right, Russia
есть я правильно смотрю что воюет Россия
and NATO are fighting at a testing ground,
и НАТО на полигоне
Ukraine, NATO is striking the territory of the
Украина нато бьёт по территории
Russian Federation, and Russia is striking
Российской Федерации а Россия бьёт по
Ukraine, well,
Украине да
naturally, I'm saying it's a testing ground, that's
ну естественно я же говорю это полигон
all, yes, look, it turns out that
всё то есть да смотри получается что
NATO is striking the territory of Russia, yes, in
НАТО бьёт по территории России да в
Nizhny Novgorod, yes, in the Saratov region,
Нижний Новгород да в Саратовскую область
in Tatarstan, Krasnodar, like the Rostov
в Татарстан Краснодар типа Ростовскую
region, yes, Crimea, which you consider
область да Крым который вы считаете
yours, Belgorod region, yes, but you do
своей Белгородская область да а вы по
n't strike NATO territory, why is that? Well,
территории НАТО не бьёте почему так
unfortunately, in this case, Russia is
ну к сожалению Россия в данном случае
considered the only country, that is,
считается единственной страной то есть
NATO is a bloc, and Russia is the only
НАТО - это блок а Россия получается одна
country that is fighting directly,
страна которая воюет непосредственно вот
in such conditions, there is nothing
в таких условиях в этом нет ничего
bad or good about this, such
плохого нет ничего хорошего таковые
conditions, no, so what is it that prohibits who,
условия нет так а что кто кто запрещает
look, if NATO attacks the territory of Russia,
смотри если НАТО атакует территорию
why can't Russia attack the
России почему Россия не может атаковать
territory of NATO countries,
территорию стран НАТО
well, you're a lawyer, right, you
ну вы же юрист правильно же вы же
understand perfectly well that here,
прекрасно понимаете что здесь
uh  if Russia strikes, for example, Poland,
ээ если Россия ударит допустим по Польше
then there will be uh oh-oh-oh if it strikes
то там будет ээ ай-ай-ай если ударит
there, then there will be oh-oh, accordingly, we have to
туда то будет ай-ай соответственно
fight in such conditions,
приходится воевать в таких условиях вот
look, do I understand correctly, yes, that
смотри я я правильно понимаю да что из
Russia is afraid oh-oh-oh, but NATO is not afraid, NATO
Россия боится ай-ай-ая а НАТО не боится
strikes on Russian territory, well, naturally, because NATO
бьёт ну естественно потому что НАТО -
is, how many 27 states or
это сколько там 27 государств или
how many 30 states, and Russia is
сколько там 30 государств а Россия - это
one state, one economy, it’s
одна одно государство одна экономика
interesting that I understood correctly, from
интересно то я правильно понял вот из
your logic that Russia is afraid of NATO, but
вашей логики что Россия боится НАТО а
NATO is not afraid of Russia, what does it
НАТО Россию не боится
mean that it is afraid, not afraid, here we
что значит боится не боится здесь не
need to think in these categories, well, as a
этими категориями нужно мыслить ну как
category, NATO strikes on
категория нато наносит удары по
Russian territory, and Russia does not
территории России а Россия не наносит
strike on NATO territory because it is
удары по территории НАТО потому что
afraid, it strikes, well, this
боится наносит удары ну а это уданот
strike on Ukraine is correct, but
удар по Украине правильно но по
NATO does not strike on territory, neither on Poland,
территории НАТО не наносит ни по Польше
nor on Germany, nor on Britain, nor on
ни по Германии ни по Британии ни по
America, but what, well, Russia
Америке да нато что ну Россия-то наносит
strikes on a training ground in Ukraine,
удары по полигону по Украине
accordingly, it is correct, and NATO,
соответственно правильно а НАТО вот
look, what’s the difference,
смотри вот НАТО какая разница да
NATO bombers fly,
натовские бомбардировщики летают себе
NATO instructors fly, in short, they fly,
натовские инструктора короче летают
accordingly, if Russia will
соответственно если Россия будет
to inflict large strong blows more there I do
наносить большие сильные удары более там
n't know with strong weapons on Ukraine
не знаю сильным оружием по Украине
accordingly they will advance further to the
соответственно они больше продвинутся к
borders of NATO accordingly what needs to be done to
границам НАТО соответственно что нужно
do NATO it is simply really
делать сделать НАТО это просто реально
stopped so that the movement of the
остановить для того чтобы движение
border would be so to speak well minimal
границы было так скажем ну минимальным
logical logical wait and why would Russia
логично логично подождите а зачем России
advance to the borders of NATO if it
продвинуться к границам НАТО если она
still won't strike the country NATO
всё равно не будет бить по стране НАТО
it is afraid so it is within the framework of a
она же боится так она же ведь в рамках
special operation carrying out tasks that No well
спецоперации выполняет задачи которые Не
look for example reached for example
ну смотри например дошла например
let's say Russia reached Poland to the
давайте дошла Россия до Польши до
border of NATO yes or for example let's imagine
границы НАТО да или например представим
that Russia will reach Finland to Estonia
что Россия так дойдёт до Финляндии до
to Latvia Lithuania and will have a
Эстонии до Латвии Литвы и будет иметь
border with NATO what next fantasy this is
границу с НАТО что дальше фантастика
fantasy it seems to me that it
это фантастика это мне кажется об этом
speaks about this well it is pointless in the sense of
говорит ну бессмысленно в смысле
fantasy what wait you do you
фантастика что вот подожди вы вы
think it is fantasy that Russia will reach
считаете фантастикой что Россия дойдёт
Estonia to Latvia and Lithuania and will have a
до Эстонии до Латвии и Литвы и будет
border with NATO
границу с НАТО
here you understand here several
иметь здесь понимаете здесь несколько
how much will reach here you understand like a
сколько дойдёт здесь понимаете как у
samurai here there is only a path you
самурая здесь есть только путь вот
understand the result is important for a samurai that is not the
понимаете важен у самурая то есть не
result but the path is important simply the samurai
важен итог а важен путь просто самурая
that is the very fact that he is moving
то есть сам факт того что он движется
here in any case Russia will not reach either the
здесь в любом случае Россия не дойдёт ни
border with Poland or the border with
до границы с Польшей ни до границы с
Estonia  neither Latvia anywhere stop
Эстонией ни Латвие никуда стоп
understand I'm telling you seriously Russia has been
понятно я я вам серьёзно скажу Россия
on the border with Poland for a long time in
уже на границе с Польшей давным-давно в
any case there will be peace in any case
любом случае мир будет в любом случае
peace will be concluded uh not on
будет заключён мир ээ не на условиях
Russia's terms not on Ukraine's terms because
России не на условиях Украины потому что
Russia in principle uh it lost this
Россия в принципе ээ она проиграла эту
war this is objectively so and it was
войну это объективно так и это было
clear well in March of the twenty-second year
понятно ну в марте двадцать второго года
this is logical but it lost from the point of view of
это логично но проиграло с точки зрения
what was declared when you
того что было заявлено когда ты вот так
said so and want to do something
скажемл и что-то хочешь сделать
accordingly it was lost
соответственно это было проиграно
accordingly here I see such a
соответственно здесь я вижу такой
convergence that is, do I understand correctly that
сход то есть я правильно понимаю что
Russia lost the war at the Ukraine training ground between
Россия войну на полигоне Украина между
Russia and NATO
Россией и НАТО проиграла
no uh I'll say that Russia those tasks
нет э-э я скажу что Россия те задачи
that it
которые она
declared on the 20th so to speak uh February it
заявила 20 так скажем э-э февраля она
accordingly wanted to take here in our country that is
соответственно хотеладесь взять наском
literally somewhere in maybe
то есть буквально где-то месяца может
three or two months there by May 9th there I don't
быть за три за два там к 9 маю там не
know on Khreshchatyk to dance uh
знаю на Крещатике протанцевать э-
special forces that they danced there I don't know
спецназов что протанцевали там не знаю
pombada like in the movie special forces yes which is
ломбаду как в фильме спецназ да который
broadcast there on our television
там транслируется по нашему телевидению
but unfortunately it didn't work out
но к сожалению это не получилось вот
accordingly we're taking a
соответственно
long time
долго
to harness quickly  let's go accordingly
запрягаем быстро едем соответственно
Russia is now
Россия сейчас долго
harnessing a lot of effort for a long time at the same time
запрягает очень много усилий при этом
applying learning from war and unfortunately
прилагает учится на войне и к сожалению
fighting as it turns out unfortunately so I
воюет как получается к сожалению так я
think so wait in short I understand in
считаю так подожди короче я понял в
general we lost the war the question is what will happen
общем войну проиграли вопрос что будет
if Russia someday
если Россия когда-нибудь
uh will have a common border with Poland
ээ будет иметь с Польшей общую границу
well in terms of what will happen well like well the
ну в плане что будет ну как бы вот ну то
same thing that will happen that you will be my
же самое что будет что вы вы будете моим
neighbor there I don't know on the site well what does it
соседом там не знаю по участку ну что
mean what will happen well look
значит что будет ну хорошо смотри
let's do it this way let's do it this way if Russia
давайте так давайте так если Россия
somewhere at least at one point reaches the
где-то хотя бы в одной точке дойдёт
border with
границей до
Poland now imagine that Russia Russia
Польши вот представьте что Россия Россия
reached Poland here Russian troops are
дошла до Польши вот российские войска
standing under the Polish
стоят под польской
border this will be a conflict with NATO I
границей это будет конфликт с НАТО я
think I think that this will not happen I
думаю я думаю что такого не будет я
think there will be a demilitarized zone
думаю будет демилитаризированная зона
such that is uh a buffer zone be it
такая то есть ээ буферная зона будь она
called there country 404 Ukraine there I do
называется там страна 404 Украина там я
n't know
не знаю
Bessarabia there whatever you like Hungary there
Бесарабия там как угодно Угорщина там
whatever it can be called but a direct
что угодно может называться но прямой
border between respectively NATO
границы между соответственно НАТО
let's say well specifically Poland and
допустим ну вот конкретно Польшей и
Russia I think there will not be well that's my
Россией я думаю не будет ну это моё
opinion cool do you want me to tell you a
мнение прикольно хотите я вам открою
secret
секрет
yes of course Russia has a border with
да конечно у России есть граница с
Poland I know  I understand perfectly well what
Польшей я знаю я прекрасно понимаю что
you are saying I mean the border
вы говорите я имею в виду ту границу про
you are talking about you were talking about Poland
которую вы говорите вы про Польшу
I am not talking about the fact that the northern ones
говорили я не говорю про то что северные
are the Baltics or Finland and so
там Прибалтика либо там Финляндия и так
on again Russia has a border with
далее ещё раз у России есть граница с
Poland where and no with the border with Poland
Польшей где а нет с граница с Польшей да
and where do we border
и где мы граничим с
Poland well in Kaliningrad you mean I I mean uh
Польшей ну в в Калининграде вы имеете в
why take
виду я я имею в виду ээ зачем брать вот
this apostrophe no need to take this uh
этот апостроф не нужно брать вот это вот
separately this one
ээ отдель вот этот
why well because well I think that in
почему ну потому что ну я считаю что
this discussion this is a bit of an
это в данной дискуссии немножко это
exception rather than a rule therefore I
исключение нежели чем правил поэтому я
need to start from the sense that you have 200
нужно отталкиваться в смысле у вас 200
km you have 200 km of land border with
км у вас 200 км сухопутной границы с
Poland what with Germany we have a
Польшей что с Германии есть у нас
border where
граница где
well it turns out with in Kaliningrad not in
ну получается с в Калининграде не в
Kaliningrad with Lithuania and with Poland only
Калининграде с Литвой и с Польшей только
no well and in the West from in the West Gdansk
не ну а на Западе от на Западе Гданьск
Poland from Kaliningrad to this to
Польша от Калининграда до этого до
Germany you from the Kaliningrad region
Германии вам от Калининградской области
to Germany you are 360 ​​km
до Германии вам 360 км
Kaliningrad region with  Lithuania and from
калининградская область с Литвой и из
Poland well look you already have a 200
Польший ну вот смотри у вас уже есть 200
km border with Poland you don't need to
км границы с Польшей вам не надо
go to Poland to attack everything you're already
доходить до Польши чтобы напа всё вы уже
there your troops missiles whatever what are
там ваши войска ракеты что угодно что же
you waiting for well I'll repeat that
вы ждёте ну я же я же повторюсь что как
in this situation it's not necessary to
бы в данной ситуации не нужно
consider there on this
рассматривать там по по данной
territory slightly different laws
территории немножко другие законы
apply and on the part of Poland no well
действуют и со стороны Поль не ну
wait look earlier when let's say
подождите смотрите раньше когда допустим
before the war there was a thirty-kilometer
до войны там тридцатикилометровый там
something or other entry I have friends in
что-то там въезд у меня друзья в
Kaliningrad they live accordingly they
Калининграде живут они соответственно в
went to Poland for groceries the Poles
Польшу гоняли за продуктами поляки
went there to fill up with gasoline that is
гоняли туда заправлялись бензином то
as if there was a completely
есть как бы там совершенно был
normal cut there are
нормальный рез там совершенно другие
slightly completely different laws so I think wait
немножко законы поэтому я считаю подожди
I'm not talking about that well look you say
я не про то ну смотрите вы же говорите
that you need to move the border there to
что вам там нужно пододвинуть границу к
NATO so you already have a border with NATO near
НАТО так уже у вас граница с НАТО возле
Finland Latvia Lithuania Estonia Poland
Финляндии Латвия Литва Эстония Польша
asked a question about Ukraine about the
задали вопрос по поводу Украины по
fact that if this and that will be the
поводу того что если вот так и так будет
border with NATO I answered you specifically
граница с НАТО я вам ответил конкретно
to your question there is no need to mix it up a little that's
на ваш вопрос не надо немножко смешивать
just what I asked you what look
вот это просто я вас спросил что смотри
you said  I'm talking about Poland, and if
вы говорили про Польшу я говорю а если у
you have a border with Poland and you do something? Well,
вас будет граница с Польшей и вы что-то
you already have a border with Poland, no, well,
Так у вас уже есть граница с Польшей нет
we talked about Ukraine,
ну мы говори говорили про Украину
right? What does Sliningrad have to do with it? No, we're
правильно причём здесь Слининград нет мы
talking about a war between NATO and Russia,
говорим про войну НАТО и России
no, no, well, we're within the framework of Ukraine - it's not
нет нет ну мы в рамках Украина - это не
Ukraine - it's only Ukraine - it's a
Украина - это только Украина - это
testing ground, we've already figured it out with you, Ukraine
полигон мы же с вами опрели украина -
is a testing ground between NATO and Russia, between,
это полигон между НАТО и Россией между
respectively, uh, Poland and,
соответственно ээ Польшей и
respectively, Russia, why are Poland
соответственно Россией почему Польшей
NATO countries, Poland is also a puppet, the
страны НАТО польша тоже марионетка
American border, Poland is an
американская граница польша - это
American puppet, don't you agree
американская марионетка вы же согласны
that you're at war with the United States,
что вы воете с Соединёнными Штатами
Britain, Germany and France? Here are the
Британией Германией и Францией вот
beneficiaries of NATO, well, NATO is not NATO,
бенефициары НАТО ну НАТО это не НАТО
Poland doesn't go to NATO, it's part of it, but these are already
польша не ходит в НАТО входит но это уже
pawns, the main thing is who's in NATO, well, what's the
пешки основное в НАТО кто ну какая
difference? Well, some of them
разница ну а на территории
are based on the territory of Poland,
соответственно Польши-то базируются там
and Turkey and Turkey are based there,
какие-то и Турция и Турция базируется
Turkey is in NATO, Turkey, respectively, I
Турция в НАТО турция соответственно
understand, yes, well, look, in short, look, I
понял да то смотри давай короче смотри я
understand, you've already screwed up with the border, the question is:
понял с границей ты уже облажался вопрос
who's the problem, no, stop, no one
такой: всё-таки кто нет стоп никто не
screwed up, no need, I'm good, everything's fine  everything everything
облажался не надо я хорошо всё всё всё
didn't screw up come on didn't screw up didn't
не облажал давай не облажался не
screw up no need you asked a question within the
облажался не надо вы задали вопрос в
framework of your question I answered
рамках вашего вопроса я ответил
specifically clearly everything everything is fine now
конкретно чётко всё всё хорошо теперь
here's the thing after all let's come back it turns out
вот такое всё-таки вернёмся получается
that it's fighting after all let's I want to
что воюет всё-таки давайте я хочу
figure out who's fighting with whom I see
разобраться кто с кем воюет я вижу
Ukraine is a testing ground so territory I'm
Украина - это полигон так территория я
fine with you everything from Testing ground yes it's fighting
же вам прекрасно всё от Полигон да воюет
on this testing ground Russia and NATO are fighting that's
на этом полигоне воюет Россия и НАТО
right
правильно
good you don't want a
хорошо вот вы не хотите чтобы вам был
clear answer but you have a lot of
чёткий ответ но у вас много осталось
weapons left that were produced in
оружия которое было произведено в
Ukraine that is not at all no
Украине то есть вообще не вообще нету
no but it's all already finished
нету но оно всё уже закончилось уже
some NATO weapons what what
какое-то натовское оружие чем чем чем
Ukraine is fighting with you will answer what difference does it make what
Украина воюет ответите вы какая разница
NATO weapons we fight with yes with NATO
чем натовским оружием воюем да натовским
weapons yes we fight with NATO weapons and
оружием да натовским оружием воюем и
with scientific weapons responsibly you
навким оружием ответственно вы сами
answered this question yourself why are you
ответили на этот вопрос зачем мне его
asking me this super that is look I'm not telling you you're telling me
задаёт супер то есть смотри я же тебе не
what weapons
говорю вот ты мне говоришь каким оружием
Ukraine is fighting with I'm telling you NATO now
воюет Украина я говорю натовским теперь
I'm telling you who Russia is fighting with NATO
я тебе говорю с кем воюет Россия с НАТО
or not with NATO
или не с НАТО
you answered your own that is
вы же сами ответили на свое то есть
Ukraine  - this is a testing ground you said it yourself:
Украина - это полигон вы сами сказали:
"Ukraine is a testing ground, we have NATO
"Украина- полигон у нас натовское
weapons" so who is Russia fighting with you
оружие" так с кем воюет Россия вы сами
answered your own question no need to go
ответили на свой вопрос не надо зать
there okay come on come on say it like this so that
туда хорошо давай давай так скажи чтобы
you are afraid to answer say Russia is
вот ты боишься ответить скажи Россия
fighting with NATO or not fighting with NATO
воюет с НАТО или не воюет с НАТО
I have already answered the question a thousand times no
я уже тысячу раз ответил на вопрос нет
you are you starting Ukraine is a testing ground just
ты ты начинаешь Украина полигон просто
say Ukraine yes is fighting with NATO or
скажи Украина да воюет с НАТО или
Ukraine no oh Russia yes is fighting with NATO
Украина нет ой Россия да воюет с НАТО
or Russia no is not fighting with
или Россия нет не воюет с НАТО
NATO I think I will repeat that now the Russian Federation is on the territory of Ukraine namely in brackets and in quotation marks testing ground yes so it is fighting with whom is it fighting with the citizens of Ukraine and But who are holding weapons in their hands yes yes that is that is Russia is not fighting with NATO I
да да то есть то есть Россия с НАТО не
answered it like I answered
я же я же ответил так как я ответил
draw your own conclusions no need to drive me
делайте выводы сами не надо мне гнать
where I don't need to be
туда где мне не нужно быть
then look Russia here it is very simple
то смотри Россия вот тут очень просто
it is on Russia is either fighting with NATO or not
это на Россия либо воюет с НАТО либо не
fighting with NATO you don't drive me here it is
воюет с НАТО ты мне не загоньте тут
inconvenient yes I have already driven you you have already you
неудобно да я тебя уже загнал ты уже ты
yourself  you're laughing
уже аж сам ржёшь
no of course it's very interesting with you but
нет с вами конечно интересно очень но
very very very interesting very
оченьочень очень интересно очень
interesting yes well look we get it Russia is
интересно да ну смотри мы поняли Россия
fighting with
воет с
Ukraine with NATO weapons and not only
Украиной натовским оружием и не только
NATO yes different countries there give us
натовским да разные страны там дают нам
weapons the question is it turns out Russia is not fighting with
оружие вопрос получается Россия не воюет
NATO it is fighting with Ukraine they are
с НАТО она воюет с Украиной
fighting with Ukraine on the territory of Ukraine in
воюют с Украиной на территории Украины в
brackets in quotation marks training
скобках в кавычках
ground quotation marks are closed bracket is
полигон кавычки закрываются скобка
closed with weapons that are
закрывается оружием которое
provided by NATO countries and DR and others
предоставляет страны НАТО и ДР и другие
yes that is it turns out look Ukraine
да то есть получается смотри Украина ей
supplies it with weapons different countries of the world not
поставляет оружие разные страны мира не
only NATO really it's a closed circle let's
только НАТО правда замкнуты круг давайте
ask another question all the same no wait no look it turns out it turns out yes Ukraine is fighting it is buying or being given weapons you for example you are fighting with North Korean weapons yes you are stealing fighting with Iranian weapons yes well Ukraine is not fighting with North Korea and Iran so they ask me: "Er, is Ukraine fighting with
вот меня спрашивают: "Ээ Украина воюет с
Iran or in North Korea?"  I say:
Ираном или в Северным Корее?" Я говорю:
"No" and I ask you: Ukraine is at war with
"Нет" а я вас спрашиваю: Украина воюет с
NATO,
НАТО
you start
вы начинаете
no, well, maybe some percentage of weapons
нет ну возможно какой-то процент оружия
exist, but I'm not talking about weapons, well,
и существует но я не про оружие ну
look
смотри
again, Ukraine is a testing ground in Ukraine,
ещё раз украина - это полигон в Украине
NATO weapons, so who is fighting with whom, is NATO
натовское оружие так кто с кем воюет
fighting with Russia or not, it's very
нато воюет с Россией или не воюет очень
simple,
просто
I've already answered you this question several times
я уже несколько раз отвечал вам на этот
no, you're not trying, you didn't say yes
вопрос нет не пытаетесь вы не сказали да
or no, well, how, well, it's just NATO, a yes or no question, do you
или нет ну как ну это просто ну НАТО
hear yes or no, well,
вопрос да или нет слышишь да или нет ну
NATO is either fighting with Ukraine or not
НАТО либо воюет с Украиной илибо не
fighting, well, yes
воюет
or no, well, this is stupid talk, well, I'm
ну да или нет ну это же гово глупо ну я
saying that at the moment, okay, yes, yes,
же говорю что в данный Хорошо да да
let's do it this way, look, Russia is fighting with
давайте так э смотрите Россия воюет с
India,
Индией
I think that no, Russia is fighting with
я думаю что нет вот Россия воюет с
Japan,
Японией
well, it seems that we are in a state of war, some
ну вроде в состоянии войны какой-то там
kind of moment there, okay,
у нас есть какой-то там момент что ладно
Russia is fighting with South Korea,
Россия воюет с Южной Кореей
uh, no, Russia is fighting with Indonesia,
ээ нет нет россия воюет с Индонезии
no, Russia is fighting with the NATO bloc,
нет россия воюет с блоком НАТО
uh, point CM above,
ээ пункт СМ выше
Russia, the Russian Federation is carrying out
россия Российская Федерация осуществляет
military operations on  territory on the
боевые действия на территории на
territory of the testing ground Ukraine yes yes yes which is
территории полигона Украина да да да
stuffed with NATO weapons
которая там натовским оружием напичкано
then look with Come on tell me who
то смотри с Давай так назови мне с кем с
Russia is fighting with whom
кем воюет Россия
Ukraine with Ukraine we have decided everything that
с Украиной с Украиной всё мы решили
means Russia is not fighting with NATO Russia is
значит у Россия не воюет с НАТО россия
fighting with Ukraine that's all why not that does
воюет с Украиной всё почему нет
n't mean that it can't fight
это не значит что он не может воевать и
with NATO stop stop stop no sorry well
с НАТО стоп стоп стоп нет извините ну
how would it be here that
как бы здесь это
means Russia is fighting with NATO
то Россия значит воюет с НАТО
where you were catching moshes I kotal well
там где вы мошей ловили я котал ну
lord well this is all stupid well don't try to
господи ну это всё глупо ну не пытайтесь
put me in the corner and what are you you are not in the
занести меня в углу а ты какой ты не в
corner you are already in a
угле ты уже в
polygon you are not in the corner you are a
многоугольнике ты не в углу ты
polygon no well
многоугольник
I answered your question
нет ну я вам ответил на вопрос
with look it turns out you said Russia
с смотри получается ты сказал Россия
is fighting with Ukraine
воюет с Украиной
yes yes unfortunately yes everything means Russia is
да да к сожалению да всё значит Россия
fighting with Ukraine here and not with NATO
тут воюет с Украиной а не с НАТО
but there is uh you can also say cold
но есть ээ также можно сказать холодная
comma or dash hybrid war with
запятая или тире гибридная война с со
NATO countries which is carried out
странами НАТО которая осуществляется
by means of troops directly from the testing
посредством войск непосредственно
ground of Ukraine etc. etc. that is war
полигона Украины и тд и тп то есть война
with Ukraine and accordingly comma and
с Украиной и соответственно запятая а
also war I understand everything I understand let's do it this way
также война всё понял понял давайте так
so we put Russia is at war with both Ukraine and
значит ставим россия воет и с Украиной и
NATO, everything is super, everything is great,
с НАТО вот всё супер супер всё молодец
we gave birth to this question, so it turns out that if
родили мы так вопрос получается да если
Russia is at war with Ukraine and NATO, we
Россия воюет с Украиной и с НАТО мы
see shelling of the territory of Ukraine, we see
видим обстрелы территории Украины видим
shelling of the territory of Russia, but we do not see
обстрелы территории России но не видим
shelling of the territory of NATO countries, right, I
обстрелы территории стран НАТО правда я
answered this question, yes, yes,
же ответил на этот вопрос да да к
unfortunately, yes or fortunately, that we did not go through
сожалению да или к счастью что не прошли
this hotline, yeah, how does it happen
эту горячую линию угу как так получается
that NATO strikes on the territory of
что НАТО наносит удары по территории
Russia, and Russia is afraid of NATO territory,
России а Россия по территории НАТО
I answered this question, here the point is
я же ответил на этот вопрос здесь дело
not whether it is afraid or not afraid, if
не в том что боится или не боится если
you do not beat someone there, I don’t know, you don’t
вы не кому-то там не знаю помурне не
beat, not that you are afraid of a person,
бьёте не того что вы боитесь человека
it’s just you because you, you don’t
это просто вы потому что вы вот вы не
beat, you don’t do this, there are
бьёте вы не делаете этого есть
certain laws,
определённые законы есть определённые
let’s say there is an alliance, right, if we
допустим есть альянс правильно если мы
encroach on it, accordingly, we will receive a
на него посягнём соответственно мы
response from there, excuse me, not
оттуда получим ответку извините меня не
from the outside, you are already receiving NATO,
со стороны вы уже получаете на НАТО уже
NATO is already shelling your territories, well, there
НАТО обстреливает ваши территории ну
is a point in that concentration, and you are
есть момент в том в концентрации и вы
precisely in the amount of aggression
вот именно в количестве той агрессии
that we can receive, the question is,
которую мы можем получить вопрос вот
your constitutions say that if on
ваши конституции там сказано что если на
half a cone is NATO aggressing against you, then you
полшишечки на вас агрессирует НАТО то
can sort of tolerate it,
можно типа терпеть
well, you know, at this point I'm not a
ну я знаете я в этом моменте я не
military strategist,
военный стратег
I don't know these subtleties, but I
я не знаю этих тонкостей но я прекрасно
understand perfectly well, I give my report, that there is a visible
понимаю даю се отчёт что идёт видна
war going on, and not all questions can be
война и не на все вопросы можно
answered unambiguously, and not from the letter of
однозначно ответить и не не с буквы
any law, I don't know from the point of
какого-либо закона там не знаю с точки
view of our constitution, your
зрения там нашей конституции там вашей
constitution, the NATO charter, or I don't know the
конституции устава НАТО там или не знаю
UN charter, all these or those moments can be
устава ООН все те или иные моменты можно
explained, unfortunately, the modern world
объяснить к сожалению современный мир
draws such rules by which it is
рисует такие правила по которым
necessary, yes, well, look, well, this is
приходится да хорошо вот смотри ну вот я
how I understand it, that these Anglo-Saxons, they are
так понимаю что вот эти англосаксы они
very cunning bugs, yes, they will, yes, they
же очень хитрые жуки да они будут да они
will continue to shell the territory of
будут дальше обстреливать территорию
Russia, the
России
question is: where is this red line after
вопрос: где эта красная линия после
which the Russian Federation authorities will
которого власть Российской Федерации
say to NATO: "Stop, for example,
скажет НАТО: "Стоп вот например
Oryol, Belgorod, Krasnodar,
Орловскую Белгородскую Краснодарю
regional lines, even as you say,
обласный линии даже как вы говорите
red lines, right?"  Yes, where do these red
красные линии да?" Да то где эти красные
lines end, in what region do you
линии заканчиваются на какой области
need to listen, listen
нужно послушать послушать
directly to what they are saying in the Foreign Ministry, for
непосредственно то что заявляют в Миде
example, they say that if there are
вот допустим говорят что если там на
attacks on the bridge, let's say from
мост учистятся атаки да допустим со
Ukraine or from NATO countries, I don't
стороны Украины там или со стран НАТО
know, it doesn't matter, then they
там не знаю неважно то соответственно
will accordingly hit the
будут бить по
hydroelectric power plants there in the Kyiv region, well, that
гидроузлам там Киевской области ну то
is, NATO, but NATO is not so, where is the red
есть НАТО а так НАТО не так где красная
line, that Russia will then respond to NATO,
линия что Россия тогда ответит НАТО
I am saying that it will respond to NATO
я же говорю что она отвечает НАТО
by striking Ukraine, I understand, I
посредством ударом по Украине я понял
understand, that is, if NATO bombs the
понял то есть если НАТО разбомбит
Crimean Bridge, Russia will not do anything to NATO, so
Крымский мост Россия ничего не сделает
it will strike Ukraine, no,
нато она будет бить по Украине да нет
why will it bomb, let's say,
почему она разбомбит допустим
some kind of hydroelectric power station,
какой-нибудь там э какого там ГЭС
some kind of hydroelectric power station in the area, yes, the hydroelectric power station is correct,
какой-нибудь в районе да гэс правильно
yes, that is, it turns out that if NATO, uh,
да то есть получается если НАТО ээ
bombs the Crimean Bridge, Russia will bomb
разбомбит Крымский мост Россия разбомбит
not in, not in a NATO country, something, but a hydroelectric power station in
не в не в стране НАТО что-то а ГЭС в
Ukraine, well, that's a testing
Украине да
ground, well, and NATO,
ну так это же полигон ну так а НАТО
what's the difference, NATO doesn't care about the testing ground,
какая разница нато пофиг на полигон
look, NATO will shoot at NATO, that's why it's
смотри НАТО типа будет стрелять на НАТО
not cold or hot, it's true, the testing
от этого же не холодно не жарко правда
ground is a ring, you understand, what's behind the
полигон - это ринг понимаете то что за
ring, what's behind the ring, there behind  the ring
рингом то что за рингом там за рингом
is your room, there is your trainer and so
есть твоя комната есть твой тренер и так
on and so forth yes yes yes but look they
далее и подобное дада да но смотрите вам
beat you in the face not in the ring they beat you behind the ring behind the
бьют морду не на ринге вам бьют за
training ground behind Ukraine yes in the
рингом за полигоном за Украиной да вам в
Belgorod region they beat you in the face in
Белгородской области бьют морду в
Tatarstan and
Татарстане и так дальше
so on well and so on ...
что всё как бы всё ребята как бы по
to Ukraine, that
взяли вилы косы и пошли на Украину то
is, I intend to, look, yes, I am
есть я вот намер смотри да вот мне
interested in this, I am simply modeling
интересно просто я так моделирую
the situation if tomorrow, yes, uh, at
ситуацию если завтра да ээ в
NATO headquarters they decide to wipe
штаб-квартире НАТО решат стереть в
Belgorod, Krasnodar and
порошок вообще Белгород Краснодар и
Rostov into dust, so will you strike NATO or will you strike
Ростов так вы ударите по НАТО или будете
Ukraine, well, I am saying that I do
по Украине бить ну я же говорю что я
not like science fiction, so I, well, I
фантастику не люблю поэтому я ну я не
will not answer this question because I do
буду отвечать на это вопрос потому что я
not even know how to answer it honestly,
даже не знаю как на него ответить честно
well, look, Belgorod, NATO is
сказать ну ну вот Белгород смотрите НАТО
simply destroying the Belgorod region, have
просто уничтожает Белгородскую область
you seen these, uh, reports, really,
вы видели эти ээ сводки правда
well, if you think so, then so I
ну раз вы считаете так значит так я
just can’t, the governor is already
просто я не могу там уже губернатор
resettling entire villages, making a gray
отселяют целые сёла делают серую зону
demilitarized zone, how many were they
демилитаризированную сколько там
saying, 200-something have already died at the hands of
говорили 200 с чем-то уже погибло от рук
NATO,
натовцев
unfortunately, there is war, nothing can be done here,
к сожалению война ничего здесь не
and when they shoot at you, it means that
и когда стреляют в тебя это значит что
sooner or later, when you shoot, it
рано или поздно когда стреляешь ты
means that the moment is not far off that they will
значит что не недалёкой момент что будут
meet you in kind, that is, it is
встречать тебе в обратку то есть это
logical, I just don’t understand,
логично просто я не я не понимаю
look, if NATO and Russia, you decided, well, there
смотрите если НАТО и Россия вы решили
is, they agreed, there is a ring of
вот вот есть они договорились есть ринг
Ukraine, let’s go here  let's fight yes they fight
Украины давай тут побьёмся да они бьются
here but NATO takes and shoots outside the ring at
тут но НАТО берёт и стреляет за ринг по
Belgorod region at Tatarstan at
Белгородской области по Татарстану по
Nizhny Novgorod region in short
Нижегородской по короче
Krasnodar region at Rostov region and
Краснодарскому краю по Ростовскому и
just stupidly hits without sparing anything and
бьёт просто тупо не жалеет ничего а
Russia is like this Well answer
Россия такая у Ну вот ответьте сами на
this question yourself I am interested in that is
этот вопрос мне самом интересно то есть
how would I say that I do not know the
как бы я сказал что я не знаю на этот
answer to this question please
ответ на этот вопрос пожалуйста вот
you can also say that because Yes my
можете и вы сказать что потому Да моё
opinion look my philistine to me
мнение смотрите моё обывательское мне
My philistine opinion is that uh
Моё обывательское мнение такое что ээ
Russia is losing the war to NATO and NATO is
Россия проигрывает войну НАТО и НАТО
increasing shelling of Russian
наращивает обстрелы российской
territory yes it is advancing for example a year
территории да продвигается например год
ago strikes there at Belgorod region
назад удары там по Белгородской области
it was news yes and now it is already
это была новость ещё да а сейчас это уже
Belgorod region is not even
Белгородская область уже даже никому не
interesting to anyone yes NATO weapons are already flying in hitting the
интересна да уже прилетает натовское
Urals at Tatarstan at
оружие бьёт по Уралу по Татарстану по
Nizhny Novgorod region that is there for
Нижегородской области то есть там на
quite a large number of kilometers
довольно большое количество километров
yes today for example NATO weapons
да сегодня например натовское оружие
hit or yesterday on the Kola
поразило или вчера на Кольском
Peninsula airfield
полуострове аэродром
Olenia everything that is working for NATO
Оления всё то есть на НАТО работает
systematically and that's all I just look I am
системно и всё я просто смотрите я
just like a resident of this training ground yes
просто как ээ житель полигона этого да
Ukraine, we understand, we understand, we
Украины мы понимаем мы понимаем мы
can't do anything, we understand that
ничего не можем сделать мы понимаем что
NATO and Russia have collided here, yes, two
тут столкнулись НАТО и Россия да две
global superpowers, and we are
глобальные сверхдержавы и мы наблюдаем
just watching, we are just watching, well, we are watching, objectively,
просто смотрим ну мы смотрим объективно
NATO is stronger, so we are for NATO at first. At first, when
НАТО сильнее поэтому мы за НАТО сначала
Russia was in the first days of the
Сначала когда Россия первые вот эти дни
special operation, when they were breaking into Kyiv,
спецоперации когда ломились на Киев у
many of us thought: "Everything has been [ __ ] on NATO now,
нас многие думали: "Всё НАТО обос сейчас
and in short, we need to greet Russia with
да и нужно короче встречать Россию
bread and salt," but in short, as the
хлебом солью" но короче как показали
first days showed, Russia was given a beating, in short, Russia
первые дни России дали звездюлей короче
ran away, everyone was like: "Oh, listen,
Россия убежала все такие: "О то слушай
together with NATO we are cool," and everyone is already
то мы вместе с НАТО крутые" и все уже
like: "We have Russia, do we have NATO?"
такие: "Нам Россия есть ли у нас НАТО?"
And for example, if Russia took
И например если бы Россия взял стукнул
Putin and hit him like Khrushchev once,
Путин по этому как Хрущёв когда-то
remember, he took off his heel and hit the podium and
помните он снял каблук и по трибуне вон
said: "We'll show you Kuskin's
бил говорит: "Мы вам покажем Куськину
mother" he wasn't afraid, he drove him to Cuba,
мать" он не боялся он загнал на Кубу
and there were missiles, the Cuban Missile Crisis, and
загнал да ракеты был карибский кризис а
what about Putin, we look, we might
что Путин получается мы смотрим мы может
want to be friends with Russia and not with
и хотели бы дружить с Россией а не с
NATO, but we look, Russia is weak, NATO is
НАТО но мы смотрим Россия слаба НАТО
stronger, why should we be with Russia if
сильнее зачем нам быть с России если у
NATO has cooler weapons, more technologically advanced weapons, and NATO
НАТО круче оружие технологичнее и НАТО
hits Russian territory, but Russia
бьёт по территории России а Россия по
doesn't hit NATO territory, and we think, damn, well,
территории НАТО нет и мы думаем блин ну
maybe NATO is cooler, well, I'm just saying it this way,
наверное всё-таки НАТО круче ну я вот
we're just ordinary
так по-простому мы ж мы же простые
Ukrainians, and we don't care who we're in the
украинцы да нам всё равно с кем быть в
bloc with, either NATO or Russia, the main thing is that
блоке либо с НАТО либо с Россией главное
whoever is stronger, we'll choose
чтобы кто был сильнее мы же выберем
strongly, maybe a small remark, but
сильно можно можно маленькую ремарку а
in principle, you had it written down
так у вас же в принципе прописано было
that you should have a non-aligned status,
что у вас должен быть внеблоковый статус
you should be neutral, independent, not
вы должны быть нейтральны независимые не
from Russia, not from the NATO bloc, and we, and
от России не от блока НАТО а мы а мы
then we, we wrote it into the constitution that
потом мы мы прописали в конституцию что
Ukraine is striving to join NATO and that Well  and how did
Украина стремится в НАТО и что Ну а как
you just take it so so sovereign yes
вы просто взяли так так сувере да
sovereign right we ourselves we form
суверенное право мы сами мы ж формируем
our constitution and we write our rules in it yes
свою конституцию и мы прописываем в ней
we looked damn form the
да мы посмотрели блин формируйте
constitution you form you had a
конституцию вы формируете вы у вас
referendum so that you form this
референдум был чтобы вы формировали эту
constitution once again the constitution is
конституцию ещё раз конституцию для
enough for the constitution there is such a
конституции достатно есть такое
constitutional majority of 300
конституционное большинство 300
deputies if there are 300 deputies out of 450
депутатов если есть 300 депутатов из 450
2 that is it can change the constitution
2 то есть она может изменить конституцию
yes
да
any law once again
любой закон
look there is such a concept
ещё раз смотри вот есть такое понятие
constitutional love
конституционный люботь
constitutional any law can be
конституционный любой закон могут могут
changed by half of the deputies and amendments to the
изменить половина депутатов а правки в
constitution 300 deputies
конституцию 300 депутатов
constitutional law once again look
конституционный закон ещё раз смотри
amendments to the constitution need 2/3 of the
правки в конституцию нужно 2/3
parliament that is 300 deputies uh
парламента то есть 300 депутатов ээ
other laws half of the parliament
другие законы половина парламента
and why in many countries amendments
а почему в во многих государствах правки
to the constitution are made through a referendum
в конституцию посредством референдума
look I am a person with a legal
посмотри я человек с юридическим
education so look yes if we
образованием так е смотри да если мы
delegate we delegate deputies yes we
делегируем мы делегируем депутатов да мы
delegate deputies and they  make
делегируем депутатов и они принимают
decisions in the same way for example who adopted the
решение так же например кто принимал
constitution of Ukraine deputies Verkhovna
конституцию Украины депутаты верховная
Rada in ninety-sixth year on June 28th it
Рада в девяносто шестом году 28 червня
was not a referendum adopted
это июня приняла не референдум принял
the constitution yes and deputies delegated by
конституцию да а депутаты делегированные
people adopted the
ээ людьми приняли
constitution because the constitutional
конституцию потому что конституционный
process is uh complicated yes it's not
процесс - это ээ сложный да это не
just like that you know let's take it now in short let's
просто так знае давай сейчас короче вот
take it and adopt it yes that is it goes through
возьмём и примем да то есть оно проходит
certain readings certain
определённые чтения определённые
hearings and so on that is yes there is a
слушания и так дальше то есть да есть
whole procedure yes that is it is not so
целая процедура да то есть это не так
easy and in many countries also uh in the
легко и во многих странах тож ээ в
constitution in the constitution yes amendments are
конституции в конституции да правки
often made and if you look at
часто делаются и если вы посмотрите в
Ukraine in Ukraine yes amendments were often made to the
Украину в Украине да часто вносились
constitution in Russia were made
правки в конституцию в России вносились
in other countries it is always a living
в других странах всегда это живой
process any legal document it is a
процесс любой юридический документ он
living document new
живой документ появляются новые
circumstances appear yes and you need to
обстоятельства да и на них нужно
react to them new laws
реагировать появляются новые законы
appear new ones appear in the chat sign under
появляются новы в чате подписть по под
certain agreements and conditions
определёнными договорами и условиями
you understand why everything changes here yes
понимаете причём здесь всё меняется да
yes so look yes look look the
да так смотрите да смотри смотрите
constitution yes the constitution is that  what did
конституция да конституция - это то что
we decide for ourselves how did we agree
мы для себя решили как мы договорились
for ourselves if we then decided let's
для себя если мы потом решили давайте
be in NATO we write down that we will be in
будем в НАТО мы прописываем что будем в
NATO if we No wait you signed an
НАТО если мы Нет подождите вы подписали
agreement on non-aligned status with No what
договор о внеблоковом с Нет какой
agreement what agreement well
договор какой договор
Budapest memorandum no stop stop stop
ну Будапештки меморандум нет стоп стоп
firstly in the Budapest memorandum there is
стоп во-первых в Будапештском
nothing at all about non-aligned
меморандуме никак ничего о внеблоковом
status the Budapest
статусе вообще нет будапештский
memorandum there is only there not a single obligation of Ukraine this is when Ukraine gave up nuclear weapons yes on the contrary Russia Great Britain France USA yes signed that they will defend Ukraine this is in the Budapest memorandum
Украину это в Будапештском меморандуме
you took on obligations America and
вы взяли на себя обязательства америка и
Russia Ukraine and there is nothing at all about non-aligned status that is
Россия Украина и там про внеблоковость
good and
вообще ничего то есть хорошо а к чему
then what is this agreement then that is well this
тогда этот договор тогда то есть это ну
memorandum it did not assume that
меморандум он он не предполагал тому что
accordingly if Ukraine gives something
соответственно если Украина отдаёт
accordingly it
что-то соответственно она что-то
receives something again look Ukraine gives up
получает ещё раз смотри украина отдаёт
nuclear weapons yes and receives protection of
ядерное оружие да а получает защиту
nuclear powers in the event of an attack on them that's how
ядерных держав в случае нападения на них
look Ukraine has never
вот так смотри э Украина нигде ни в
committed itself in any agreement not to
каком договоре не обязывалась не
join blocs  to join or not to
вступать в блоки вступать или не
join blocs yes this is the sovereign right of
вступать в блоки да это суверенное право
each country this is written in the UN statute
каждой страны это в статуте ООН записано
no there cannot be an agreement that the country will not
не не может быть договор что страна не
join any blocs Russia is
будет вступать в какие-то блоки россия
joining the CSTO Russia joined the
вон вступает в ОДКБ россия вступила в
military bloc
блок военный вступила
Armenia joined Belarus joined
армения вступила Беларусь вступила
look why Belarus can join
смотри почему Беларуси можно вступать в
some blocs but Ukraine can't
какие-то блоки а Украине нельзя
unfortunately geopolitical laws in general
к сожалению геополитические вообще
say the opposite there are no
законы говорят об обратном нету никаких
geopolitical laws you came up with
геополитических законов это вы придумали
such a phrase geopolitical law no well what does it
такую фразу геополитический закон нет ну
mean what does it mean we will come up with such a
что значит что значит мы придумаем такую
phrase well there is a concept of geopolitics there is a
фразу ну есть же понятие геополитики
concept and what well the concept of
есть же понятие а что ну понятие
geopolitical law - you just came up with
геополитический закон- это вы придумали
it well you have
только что его ну вот у вас есть
some kind of strategic interest you have
стратегический интерес какой-то у вас
this who doesn't have well you state
это у кого нет вот у вас у государства у
country so there is a strategic interest and
страны так есть стратегический интерес и
what for example joining NATO and the
какой например вот вступить в НАТО и
European Union is our strategic
Евросоюз - это наш стратегический
interest
интерес
and why that is yes in ninety-two
а почему то есть да в девяносто втором
let's say you didn't have this
году допустим у вас не было этого
strategic interest because it is
стратегического интереса потому что
absolutely correct when for example the
абсолютно правильно когда например
United States of America uh appeared  in the
Соединённые Штаты Америки ээ появились в
15th century, yes, they also did not have
XV столетии да у них тоже не было
any strategic interest when
какого-то стратегического интереса когда
you, for example, let's say in the
у вас например ээ скажем в девяностом
nineties, you also did not have any
году у вас тоже не было каких-то
interests, we are developing, we are
интересов мы развиваемся мы так мы
friends with other countries, we believe that we have,
дружим с другими странами мы считаем что
why do you think that Russia does
вот у нас почему вы считаете что Россия
not Because we want to consider, look,
не Потому что мы хотим считать смотри
this is our right, where should we integrate,
это наше право куда нам интегрироваться
our sovereign right, the answer to the question:
наше суверенное право ответ на вопрос:
why does Russia not have the same
почему у России нет такого же
sovereign right to develop the same
суверенного права развивать те же самые
moments,
моменты
why does Russia not have such a sovereign right, the
почему у России нет такого суверенного
same moments that you
права же самые моменты о которых вы
just mentioned,
сейчас сказали
Russia, look, since Ukraine
росси у России смотри поскольку Украина
was in a non-bloc status, oh my
была в неблоковом статусе
God, stop, stop, one second, one second, one second,
господи стоп стопсто секунду секунду
and now, you
секунду секунду а сейчас вот у меня
see, in Russia, yes, there is such a
понимаешь вот в России да есть такой
moment, no, but I would like it to be
момент нет а мне хотелось бы чтобы
just really, here it is, I want to conduct
просто реально вот она я хочу вот именно
my policy exactly like this, look, here I
так политику свою вести смотри вот я я
am, I am explaining to you, look, Russia
тебе я тебе объясняю смотри у России
has, just like Ukraine, a sovereign
есть так же как у Украины суверенное
right to join any blocs and alliances,
право вступать в любые блоки и союзы вы
for example, you joined the CSTO military bloc with
например вступили в военный блок ОДКБ с
Armenia, Kyrgyzstan, Kazakhstan
Арменией там Киргызстаном Казахстаном
Belarus wait now I Ukraine
Белоруссию подожди теперь я Украина
refused no we refused yes
отказалась нет вот мы отказались да вот
you uh joined it's your right you
вы ээ вступили это ваше право вы
joined the BRICS organization it's
вступили там в организацию БРИКС это
your right yes so Ukraine also
ваше право да так вот Украина также
has the right to join and be friends with anyone you
имеет право вступать и дружить с кем
want to attack others you don't have the
угодно нападать на других вы не имеете
right your sovereign right yes be friends with
права ваше суверенное право да дружить с
whoever you want unite with whoever you want
кем хотите объединяться с кем хотите
trade with whoever you want but you don't have the
торговать с кем хотите но у вас нет
right to attack another when you are a
права нападать на другого когда вы
person when you are a person Stop look when you are a
человек когда вы чело Стоп смотри когда
person yes uh you say: "I
вы человек да вот ээ вы говорите: "Я
want to be friends with Petya" it's your right and
хочу дружить с Петтей" это ваше право а
when you go and beat Ivan's face in because
когда вы идёте бить морду Ивану потому
he is friends with Petya it's already a violation
что он дружит с Петей это уже нарушение
really I
правда
agree well the situation was different
согласен ну ну ситуация была другая
Russia didn't come because it just
россия же зашла не из того что просто
said that it was Ukraine again
сказал что так это Украина ещё раз ещё
look again Russia entered the territory of
раз смотри Россия зашла на территорию
Ukraine in 2014 all this is
Украины в четырнадцатом году всё это
aggression here it is clear Ukraine
агрессия тут понятно украина ещё раз
look again Ukraine yes has the right to join the
смотри Украина да имеет право вступать в
blocs it wants and how it wants
те блоки которые хочет и как хочет
no you understand what it means you understand
нет понимаете что значит вот понимаете
you as a lawyer yourself say that you are a lawyer
вы как юрист сами говорите что вы юрист
you  say what does your mean that is if
вы говорите что значит ваш то есть если
you say that accordingly it is necessary to
вы говорите что соответственно нужно
use legal concepts that is to say it
юридическими понятиями пользоваться то
entered the territory of Crimea accordingly under a certain
соответственно вошла под определённым
so to speak moment right on the
так скажем моментом правильно на
territory of so to speak Donetsk under what and at the
территорию так скажем донецких под каким
same moments the
та по таким же самым моментам
occupation forces entered
оккупационные силы вошли
no well this is from the point of view of jurisdiction it is
нет ну это с точки зрения юрисдикции это
different from what
же отличается нежели от того что как
was in Donetsk Donbass and so
было на на Донецке Донбассе там и так
on the same thing entered look in this
далее то же самое зашли смотри в этом
in Crimea the troops entered from February 26 to 27 of the
в Крыму войска зашли с 26 на 27 февраля
fourteenth year in Donetsk and
четырнадцатого года в Донецкой и
Lugansk regions on April 12 of the
Луганской области 12 апреля
fourteenth
четырнадцатого
year the same thing that is
года то же самое
one to one one to one that is in
то есть один в один один в один то есть
fact that is you think that the war has been
фактически то есть вы считаете что война
going on since the fourteenth year since the
идёт с четырнадцатого года с
fourteenth year yes the war began on the
четырнадцатого года да война началась в
night of February 26 to 27 of the fourteenth
ночь с 26 на 27 февраля четырнадцатого
year with the occupation of Crimea
года с оккупацией Крыма
well okay and another question and why then did
ну хорошо а другой вопрос а почему тогда
n't you send volunteers if
вы добровольцев не отправили если
Ukraine accordingly captured the territory of Crimea
Украина территорию Крыма соответственно
as you think super super yes
захватили как вы считаете супер супер да
good question good  the question is why
хороший вопрос хороший вопрос почему
Russia did not send volunteers
Россия не отправила добровольцев
to recapture Kherson now no no no you will
отвоевать Херсон сейчас нене не вы
answer the question I am asking why because there was
ответите на вопрос я я спрашиваю почему
no strength because I am
потому что не было сил потому что я
explaining Ukraine yes it could not physically
объясняю украина да не могла физически
because Russia
потому что Россия
we considered Russia a friendly
мы считали Россию дружной страно
country and we did not have a
дружественной страной да и у нас не было
defense strategy that
оборонной стратегии что на нас будет
Russia would attack us and take away our
нападать Россия да и отжимать у нас
territories so Russia was not considered in
территории вот Россия не считалась в
Ukraine yes a strategic enemy
Украине да стратегическим противником
that could attack and in our
который может напасть и в нашей
defense strategy there was no attack we
оборонной стратегии не было нападения мы
held joint exercises with Russia
с Россией совместные ущения проводили
also true wait so
также правда вот подожди так вот так
look and here Russia yes having attacked on the night of the
смотри и вот Россия да напав в ночь с
2nd to the 27th having transferred
2шего на двадцать седьмого перебросив
it was preparing for this preparing
она готовилась к этому готовилась
preparing having transferred huge landing
готовилась перебросив огромные десантные
uh forces yes having blocked military units so having
ээ силы да блокировав военные части так
blocked uh military forces in Crimea that's
блокировав ээ военные силы в Крыму вот и
all that is why that is Ukraine physically
всё поэтому то есть Украины физически не
could not yes capture uh these
получалось да захватить ээ вот эти
Russian troops that entered Crimea en masse
российские войска которые массово вошли
everything is very simple now look
в Крым всё очень просто теперь смотрите
now when Ukraine yes uh in the Donetsk
теперь когда Украина да ээ на в Донецкой
region yes when the Russians began to enter
области да когда россияне начали входить
Ukraine because of the landscape  because of
Украина из-за ландшафта из-за
geographical features yes it was easier there
географических особенностей да там проще
because the entrance to Crimea is through a narrow
было потому что в Крым вход через узкий
isthmus which was completely
перешей который полностью
controlled by the Russian Federation and it
контролировался Российской Федерацией да
physically transfers forces they fought with the
и физически перебрасывает си воевали с
militias wait it was impossible
ополченцами силы подожди невозможно было
yes in the Donetsk region yes absolutely
да в Донецкой же области да абсолютно
normal
нормально
Ukraine yes uh fought since
Украина да э-э воевала с четырнадцатого
2014 first recaptured these territories
года отвоёвывала сначала эти территории
because the Ukrainian army was not
потому что украинская армия не была
so strong that it would immediately fight both in Crimea and
такая сильная чтобы она сразу и на Крым
there so it fought so absolutely
и туда воевать вот воевала вот абсолютно
normal you see and moreover look
нормально видишь и больше того смотри
when Russia attacked Ukraine in
когда Россия напала на Украину в
2014 oh in
четырнадцатом году ещё ой в двадцать
24 full-scale in 202 yes in
четвёртом году полномасштабно в двадцать
202 Ukraine also
втором да в двадцать втором Украина тоже
some territories for example Luhansk
некоторые территории например Луганскую
region our troops withdrew why because it was
область отошли наши войска почему потому
not possible to hold on to part of
что не получилось удержать с части
Kharkov region for example there Kupinsk
Харьковской области например там Купинск
yes uh was surrendered and so on Russia
да ээ был сдан и так дальше россия
captured it on the run yes and for example others were
захватила бегом да а например другие там
able to defend the amounts there and others then
суммы смогли отстоять и другие потом
gathered forces recaptured Kharkov region
собрали силы отбили Харьковскую область
true they recaptured recaptured Kherson no no I
правда отбили отбили Херсон нет не я
understand you are a little off track  go I'm
понял вы немножко в сторону ходите я
saying that it turns out that Ukraine
говорю что то есть получается Украина
fought with the militias of Donbass and
воевала с ополченцами Донбасса и
Lugansk, not with any militias, no, with
Луганска не какими ополченцами нет с
Russian troops,
российскими войсками
what militias, no, you'll come up with something,
какие ополченцы нет ты что-то придумаешь
what kind of militias,
какие ополченцы
they fought with the militias that were in
они воевали с ополченцами которые были в
Crimea, that is, there were militias there and there, no, not there, not that,
Крыму то есть и там и там были ополчены
and there and there were
не не там не та и там и там были
Russian troops, no, well, the militia, that
российские войска нет ну ополчение то
is, you want to say that there
есть вы хотите сказать что в Крыму не
was no people's militia in Crimea, no, there
было ополчения народного не было нет это
were Russian troops, and collaborators
были российские войска да и коллаборанты
who were recruited by Russian troops, that's
которых набирали российские войска вот и
all, you yourself were born in Crimea, your relatives are there,
всё сам родился в Крыму там родственники
but I don't care where you were born,
же да мне всё равно где вы родились ещё
look again, there were Russian troops there and there,
раз смотрите и там и там были российские
everything was recorded, and the OSCE and the UN are
войска зафиксированы все и ОБСЕ и ООН
clearly everywhere, and Russian troops,
чётко есть всюду и российские войска
well, why in the Don, in the Donetsk
ну хорошо почему вот в Доне в Донецкой
region, who? Let's do it this way, who shot down the
области кто Давайте так кто сбил
Malaysian Boeing, the
малайзийский Боинг
militias or Russian troops
ополченцы или российские войска
at this training ground,
на данном полигоне
so it's
так
possible, anything is possible, I
возможно возможно всё что угодно я
honestly don't know, look, the point is not that
честно сказать я не знаю смотри дело в
you don't know, but
том не дело в том что вы не знаете а уже
it already is  look at the court decision the
ж то ж уже есть посмотрите решение суда
decision of the international court on this
решение международного суда по вот этому
shooting down of the Boeing everything was proven yes it was shot down by a
сбитию Боинга всё доказали да был сбит
Russian Buk that came from
российским буком который приехал с
Russian territory from a military unit they
территории России с воинской части
established the military unit they established
установили воинскую часть установили
what kind of Buk when the launch took place when it
какой бук когда был пуск когда он
arrived back everything is
приехал назад всё есть
possible I don't I won't deny I do
возможно я я не я не буду отрицать я я
n't know this is the moment well this is
не знаю это момент ну это это же это же
not the militia yes they took a Buk somewhere in
не ополченцы да взяли где-то бук в
Russia yes they brought it to a military unit
России да воинской части привезли
fired and took it back to Russia we don't
выстрелили и увезли назад в России мы не
sli only one let's say fact about the
сли только один допустим факт по поводу
bong I understand perfectly well that 300
бонга я прекрасно понимаю что 300
people died this is a big tragedy this is
человек погибло это большая трагедия это
certainly but I'm talking about
безусловно но я про я про другое
I'm talking about something else a little I'm talking about something else that is to say oh well then to
немножко говорю я про другое говорю то
him Russia I'm talking about
есть очм то ему росси я же говорю
Russian troops and there were Russian troops in Crimea
российские войска и в Крыму были
and there were
российские войска и в Донецке были
Russian troops in Donetsk can you
российские войска можно можно вопрос
ask a question look in 2014
задать вот смотрите в четырнадцатом году
a-a the territory of Crimea became Russian
а-а территория Крыма стала российской
territory and the territory of Donbass became
территорией а территория Донбасса стала
accordingly well supposedly there independently
соответственно ну якобы там независимо
there so to speak hung in an ice hole
там так скажем подвисла ээ в проруби
accordingly why didn't you fight with
соответственно почему вы воевали не с
Russia directly with Crimea  oh yeah and
Россией непосредственно с Крымом э да а
fought so to speak with these
воевали так скажем с этими вот
pseudo-republics I already
псевдореспублики я ж тебе я ж тебе уже
answered you look if you don't understand yes and
ответил смотри если ты не понимаешь да и
in 2014 both the territory of
в в четырнадцатом году и территория
Crimea and the territory of Donetsk and Lugansk yes
Крыма и территория Донецка и Луганска да
they became an occupied part of Ukraine
они стали оккупированной частью Украины
how Russia formalized for itself that there were
как там Россия оформила для себя что там
some quasi republics and it seemed like they
какие-то квази республики а там вроде
took over this doesn't interest us at all yes
взялсята это нас вообще не интересует да
Russian troops came there established
там пришли российские войска установили
their control and that's it yes but Ukraine in
свой контроль и всё да вот Украина в
accordance with certain
соответствии с определёнными
geographical features yes and the
географическими особенностями да и
presence of their armed forces could not
наличие у них вооружённых сил не могла
conduct such a wide front and could not
вести такой широкий фронт и не могла да
break through to Crimea because the entrance to
прорываться в Крым потому что вход в
Crimea was through certain isthmuses which were
Крым через определённые перешеи которые
immediately mined yes which was
сразу поминировали да который был
completely controlled by the Russian
полностью контролирся Российской
Federation on the territory of Donbass yes yeah it
Федерацией на территории Донбасса да э
was possible to do this why because the
можно было это делать почему потому что
territory uh assumed the coverage of a
территория ээ предполагала охваты
large territory yes coverage of cities which is what
большой территории да охваты городов что
Ukraine did if you look yes
и делала Украина если ты посмотришь да
if wait no it's not a lie which is what
если подожди не не обман что и делала
Ukraine did yes if you tell the question
Украина да если ты рассказываешь вопрос
here it's interesting for the sake of interest do you think
вот интересно ради интереса ты считаешь
that in 2014  in
что в четырнадцатом году в
April Ukraine fought with some
апреле Украина воевала с какими-то
miners in Donbass
шахтёрами так на Донбассе
well for me it's a difficult question can't be a
ну для меня это сложный вопрос не могуть
question question what did these miners fight with where did
вопрос вопрос а чем воевали эти шахтёры
they get their weapons weapons weapons
чем откуда у них оружие оружием оружием
what kind of weapons
каким
definitely not NATO yes well where did the
ну однозначно не натовским да ну откуда
miners get their tanks for example
вот откуда у шахтёров танки например
armored personnel carriers well I thought in April
бронетранспортёры ну я думал в апреле
these were still the remains of the weapons that
это ещё были остатки оружия которые там
were there in the units which in which
были в частях которые на какие в каких
units no no no no look these are fables
частях нет нет нет нет смотри это басни
tell me in which unit no this is when he
скажи в какой части нет вот это когда
says in the units I ask in which where was the
говорит в частях я спрашиваю в какой где
unit that they dismantled there was not well
там была часть которую они разобрали не
that in the Donetsk region there was not a
было ну что в Донецкой области не было
single unit what well tell me which
ни одной части какая ну скажи какая
unit in which they dismantled there tanks
часть в которой разобрали там танки
for example in which unit yes I have no idea I
например в какой части да я понятия не Я
have no idea So here you have no idea
пред Так вот вот вот не имеешь понятия
so look you asked my opinion I
так смотри вы моё мнение спросили я вам
tell you that so and I say look for
говорю что так а я говорю смотри за вот
10 years have passed already yes name me at least
прошло 10 лет уже да назови мне хоть
one unit from which they took these miners
одну часть из которой они эти шахтёры
there military these googled now
взяли там военные эти вот нагугли сейчас
from which unit they took military tanks
с какой части они взяли военные танки
yes I won't I won't google  you google no no
да не буду я не гуглить вы загуглите
such thing that's exactly no that is to
нету нету такой вот вот именно нету то
say on the territory of Donetsk region there
есть на территории Донецкой области не
was not a single military unit again on the
было ни одной части воинско ещё раз на
territory of yes Donetsk region
территории да Донецкой области
occupied no military units from
оккупированная никаких военных частей из
which equipment was taken there there are no such that is to say there is not a
которых там брали технику нету таких то
single unit in Donetsk there is not a
есть нет ни одной части на Донецко нету
single unit yes where were the tanks and
ни одной части да где были там танки и
so on yes no that's the region
так дальше да не вот области тоже не
was not there either yes tell me tell me well no well that is to say you
было да на назовите мне назовите ну не
think that there definitely was not
ну то есть вы считаете что точно не было
I think that there was not yes because
я считаю что не было да потому что у нас
look we have uh borders with Russia yes
смотрите у нас ээ границы с Россией да
these military units so they were still from the
эти военные части так они ещё были из
Soviet Union yes and in Ukraine yes in
Советского Союза да вот и в Украине да в
Ukraine it was not formed we had no
Украине не формировалось у нас не было
such thing as keeping uh military units near the
такое что держать ээ воинские части под
border with Russia there because Russia was
границей с Россией там потому что Россия
not considered uh a threat yes tell me
не считалась ээ угрозой да назовите мне
where in Donetsk there is some kind of tank
где в Донецке там какая-то танковая
military unit at least one really well that is to say
военная часть хоть одну вот реально
you claim that there
ну то есть вы утверждаете что ни одной
was not a single unit I claim yes I claim
части не было я утверждаю да я утверждаю
that there were none there if we see Crimea
что никаких там вот если мы видим Крым
yes Crimea we see the seizure of military units
да Крым мы видим захваты воинских частей
there were Ukrainian military units  there were
там были украинские воинские части были
captures we see videos we can name
захваты мы видим видео можем назвать
military units some airfields which were captured
воинские части какие-то аэродромы какие
yes military some uh
были захвачены да военные какие ээ
tank and so on yes what was
танковые и так дальше да какое было
captured can I hum
захвачено можно можно я загуду вот
let's go let's go
давайте давайте
Richterovinsky units
ричатровинский части
and while you google here's an interesting question
а пока гуглишь вот интересный вопрос
look do I understand correctly that some
смотри я правильно понимаю что какие-то
miners were able uh to recapture a bunch of
шахтёры смогли э-э там отбить кучу
territories from the Ukrainian
территорий у украинской
army and the Russian army can't do it oh well
армии а российская армия не может это
here enough something is written here
ой ну тут достаточно что-то тут пишут
now well yes that is some miners
сейчас ну да то есть какие-то шахтёры 8
held back the onslaught of the Ukrainian army for 8 years with the
лет сдерживали натиск украинской армии
support of NATO I wait you I did
при поддержке НАТО я вам подождите я вам
n't answer this question come on come on well
не ответил на этот вопрос давай давай ну
you search search search come on
ты ищи ищи ищи давай
Ukraine so
украина так войска
Ukrainian troops in Donbass
Украины в Донбассе
so here something from the fourteenth to the
так тут что-то с четырнадцатого по
twenty-second
двадцать второй
year of
год
Donbass no well I don't believe that there is not a single
донато года не ну я не верю что ни одной
military unit no don't find look look
воинской части нет не не найди смотри
this is just a
смотри это ж вот это ж просто захват на
capture of a military unit by militias
захват воинской части ополченцами ну
really damn there is a video of them
реально блин там видео как они там
taking out in short these tanks planes come on
вывозят короче эти танки самолёты давай
well show me show me
ну показывай показывай
well as of March 1st of the fifteenth year
ну вот на 1 марта птнадцатого года по
according to the Ministry of Defense of Ukraine on the
данным Министерства обороны Украины на
territory of Donetsk Luhansk region
территории Донецкой Луганской области
there are more than 13,000
насчитывается более 13.000
servicemen well that is Russian
военнослужащих ну то есть российские
troops in this in Donetsk region what does this have to do with it this is
войска в этом в Донецкой области причём
already
тут это это уже пятнадцатый год уже
fifteen years already crammed you tell me where where in Donetsk region and what part of the military was captured yes militants Zaburg we can through your internet just I don't have I so I look I have already googled I have been googled through your internet all these 10 years and
интернет гуглил уже все эти 10 лет и не
could not find no such well no it seems
мог найти нету такого нумне мне кажется
strange to me that on the territory of the region it
странным что на территории области мне
seems to me in any region look it
кажется на любой области вот смотри мне
seems to me somehow strange yes what so
кажется как-то странным да что вот во
far it seems like Russia did not attack in
пока вроде как Россия не напала в
twenty-second yes for 8 years Donbass
двадцать втором году да 8 лет Донбасс
held out though look Ukraine
держался правда смотри Украина
shelled Donbass for 8 years and not just
обстреливала Донбасс 8 лет и не просто
shelled Donbass heroically fought
обстреливала Донбасс героически сражался
though it also held back the onslaught there were
правда он же тоже сдерживал натиск были
battles and so on and the question is
бои и так дальше да вопрос
what this Donbass  fought all these 8 years with
чем этот Донбасс воевал все эти 8 лет
weapons that represented,
оружием которое представляло
respectively, the Russian Federation
соответственно Российской Федерации
oh stop stop stop those weapons were not
оу стоп стоп стоп то оружие всё-таки не
captured somewhere and the weapons were
там где-то захватили а оружие
represented by the Russian Federation to
представляла Российская Федерация
Donbass yes 8 years according to the parental
Донбассу да 8 лет по родительным
treaty between states there stop stop stop no no no no no
договора между государствами там стоп
what
стоп стоп нет нет нет нет нет какими
what states well an
какими государствами
independent republic so
ну независимая республика так
independent stop stop Russia recognized
независимая стоп стоп россия признала
Russia Russia recognized the DPR and LPR when
Россия россия признала ДНР и ЛНР когда
only
только
in the twenty-second year in the twenty-second
в двадцать втором году в двадцать втором
year yes before the twenty-second year it
году да до двадцать второго года она
recognized with with unrecognized
признавать с с непризнанными
republics no no no stop Russia it
республиками нет нет нет стоп россия она
could not if it does not recognize then it
не могла если она не признаёт значит она
cannot make an agreement Russia Russia
не может делать договор россия Россия
recognized once again Russia recognized the
признавала ещё раз Россия признавала
territories of Ukraine
территории Украины их
it recognized them as separate republics no no
она отдельными республиками признала нет
Russia recognized them as republics before the
нет Россия признала республиками перед
SVO a couple of days before independent
СВО за пару дней независимыми
republics it recognized them that they
республиками она признала их что они
are republics like that it recognized
есть республики такие вот она признала
them independent yes that is that this is not
их независимыми да то есть что это не
part of Ukraine but these are separate countries it
часть Украины а это отдельные страны она
recognized the fact that such a
факт признала о том что существуют такие
resource exists but did not recognize their sovereignty you,
ресурс но не признала их суверенитет вы
as a lawyer, understand perfectly well
же как юрист сами же прекрасно понимаете
that
что
it recognized that there is  republics but did not
она признала что есть республики но не
recognize their sovereignty as sovereignty
признала их суверените как суверените
it recognized this is that they are
она и признала вот это есть что они
sovereign it recognized that they are all
суверенные она признала что всё они
independent sovereign states
независимые суверенные государства
could not provide
не могла предоставлять тогда
humanitarian aid then again look so
гуманитарную помощь ещё раз смотри так
tell me yes tell me why why
вот расскажи мне да расскажи мне почему
could not it trade with them but
почему она не могла торговать с ними но
could provide humanitarian aid could not could not
могла предоставлять гуманитарную помощь
trade and
не могла не могла торговать и
humanitarian could not but this
гуманитарную не могла по это
humanitarian aid look this is the territory of
гуманитарную помощ смотри это территория
Ukraine well Russia the question is that Russia
Украины ну Россия вопрос что Россия не
could not supply Russia could not
могла поставлять Россия не могла
supply humanitarian aid there stood
поставлять туда гуманитарную помощ стоял
providing humanitarian aid and
предоставлял гуманитарную помощь и об
shouted about it so here I am explaining to you
этом кричал так вот вот я тебе объясняю
yes under the guise of humanitarian aid they
да под видом гуманитарной помощи на
drove weapons to Donbass these
Донбасс загоняли оружие вот эти
trucks then drove weapons under the guise of
грузовики тогда гнали оружие под видом
humanitarian aid yes so look
гуманитарной помощи да так вот смотри
tell me yes under what agreement yes and
расскажи мне да по какому договору да и
when you are really the first you are the first
когда вот ты реально первый ты первый
person in the Russian Federation who
человек в Российской Федерации который
now be careful because what
сейчас будь осторожен потому что то что
you are saying uh a little falls under the
ты говоришь ээ немножко подпадает про
fakes uh about the armed forces because
фейки э про вооружённые силы потому что
your state officially denies
ваше государство официально отрицает
any  help Donetsk and Lugansk
любую помощь донецкую и луганскую
military before they were recognized in
военную до того как признали их в
2022 think about it now
двадцать втором году подумай вот сейчас
now look because I am a blogger I am
сейчас смотри потому что я блогер я
posting these conversations these conversations will be
выкладываю эти разговоры эти разговоры
seen in Russia including by
увидят в России в том числе и
investigators I warn you think
следователи я тебя предупреждаю подумай
carefully because your state on
аккуратно потому что ваше государство на
all international uh platforms denies
всех международных ээ площадках отрицает
any military assistance uh to Donetsk and
любую военную помощь ээ Донецку и
Lugansk before they were recognized in
Луганску до того как их признали в
if you are brave because I know yes
если ты смелый потому что я то знаю да
that they supplied weapons but they will
что они поставляли оружие но они
deny it and whoever says this in
отнекится и кто вот это заявляет в
Russia is considered this you have a
России считается это у вас же вышел
law on fakes about the Russian army
закон о фейках о российской армии потому
because officially the Russian army did not
что официально российская армия ничего
supply anything even now a very important
не поставляла даже сейчас очень важный
moment in my life tell me did Russia
момент в своей жизни скажи мне Россия
supply Donetsk and Lugansk weapons
поставляла донецкую и луганскую оружие
before 2022 yes or no
до двадцать второго года да или нет
I will repeat
я повторюсь
I am specifically answering your question and I am
я конкретно отвечаю на ваш вопрос а
perfectly aware of the full responsibility of
прекрасно осознаю всю ответственность
everyone there I do not know the moments that you
всех там не знаю моментов которых вы
warned I assume that
предупредили я предполагаю что возможно
perhaps such a situation could have happened
возможно такая ситуация и могла быть
why wait stop perhaps I understand that it is
почему стой стоп возможно я понял то
already possible they did not supply
есть уже уже возможно уже не поставляли
but perhaps I am listening specifically I am this  I didn't
а возможно я слушаю конкретно я этого не
do it, that is, I'll give it to you ruble,
делал то есть я его руб я вам дам
you specifically
конкретно вы
already probably because weapons just like that, they don't
уже возможно потому что оружие просто
appear from there,
так оно не не оттуда не появляется
right? I don't hear or
правильно я сейчас что не не слышу не
see now, I understood, that is, you were
вижу я понял то есть вы 2 минуты назад
telling it so clearly 2 minutes ago, yes, let me ask you,
так чётко рассказываете да вот я спроси
so what did they fight with, you said Russia
так чем они воевали вы так Россия
supplied it, and now it's possible it supplied it means it
поставляла а теперь возможно поставляла
supplied it means it
значит значит поставляла я говорю что
supplied it means it supplied it's possible I'm saying
значит поставляла говорю возможно я
that I don't know specifically, well,
говорю что я Я конкретно не знаю ну
maybe that's how it is, that's all you do, you do
возможно это так оно и есть всё то ты
n't know it's yours, you understood it's
так то ты не знаешь это твоё всё понял
your assumption, yes, yes, I don't rule out, I
это твоё предположение да да не исключаю
repeat, I don't rule out the fact that
повторюсь я не исключаю этот факт что
Russia could, yes, that is, it could supply it, or it could
Россия могла да то есть могла поставлять
not supply it, you don't know,
а могла не поставлять ты не знаешь
of course not, but as for logic, stop, according to the
конечно нет но я как по логике стоп по
logic of things, I understand perfectly well that it's
логике вещей я прекрасно понимаю что
possible that this is so, look, well,
возможно это так так смотри ну и
Belarus could supply it, or it could not
Беларусь могла поставлять а могла не
supply it's true, and anyone could
поставлять правда и кто угодно мог
supply it, and Iran could supply it, or it could
поставлять и Да и Иран мог поставлять
not supply it, so the question is, whose
мог не поставлять так вопрос так чьим
weapons did the Donbass fight against Ukraine with for 8 years,
оружием воевало 8 лет Донбасс против
I said it, I answered this question
я же сказал я же ответил на этот вопрос
three times already, probably, no, you now
уже трижды наверное не не вы теперь
said that you're not sure  could have
сказали что вы не уверены могла
supplied or could not have supplied
поставлять а могла не поставлять
we are not in court so that I can just say that
мы не в суде чтобы я просто говорил что
this is yes this was so and so I
это вот да это было так и так вот я это
saw it no well before this no don't look before
видел не ну до этого не не смотрите до
this you were so confident in
этого вы вы настолько были уверены в
yourself and said: "Yes because Rofia
себе и сказали: "Да потому что Рофия
supplied and now somehow
поставляла а теперь как-то
I don't see I don't see anything funny a
я я не вижу не вижу ничего смешного
completely normal discussion and here is
совершенно нормальная дискуссия и вот
feigned laughter it is of no use to us" no this is
наигранный смех он ни к чему нас" нет
not feigned this is real laughter
это это не наигранный это реальный смех
this is real I just visualized how
это реальный я просто визуализировал как
you felt in yourself this FSB
вы ощутили в себе вот эту фэсбэшную
mop yes inner core yes such and
швабру да внутренний стержень да такой и
as if and thought it is necessary to say that it
как бы и подумали надо сказать что
was possible and it was not possible yes no
возможно было а возможно не было да нет
wait well what should I say I did
подождите ну а что я должен сказать я
n't see this I don't know I am saying that
это не видел я это не знаю я говорю что
A you don't know everything everything
А не знаете всё всё
stop you know you don't know I am saying that according to the
стоп знате не знаете я же говорю что по
logic of things according to the logic of things I think
логике вещей по логике вещей я считаю
that it is possible that it was so where from it could
что возможно так оно и было отку откуда
come from logically logically yes but you
ему там взяться логично логично да но вы
don't know the borders borders with whom borders with
не знаете границ границы с кем границы с
Donetsk-Luhansk region with whom it passes
Донецко-Луганской области с кем проходит
from the
с со
side of Belarus no accordingly
стороны Беларуси нет соответственно
only  from the side of Russia and Ukraine, that's
только со стороны России и Украины
right, respectively, if Ukraine is
правильно соответственно если Украина
fighting with these regions, then where did the
воюет с этими областями значит откуда
weapons come from, then from the other side there are weapons,
оружие взято значит с другой стороны
well, that's logical, look at the facts that
оружие ну это логично смотрите фактов
someone brought them, I don't know, I don't know
того что кто-то привозил я не знаю не
everything, you don't know. That's
знаю всё вы не зна Вот всё так и скажите
it, tell me, I don't
я не знаю вот так логика но логика
know, that's how logic works, but
говорит об обратном вот да я не знаю но
logic says the opposite, yeah, I don't know, but logic says the opposite, I accepted everything,
логика говорит об обратном всё принял
damn, no, well, what's wrong, well, I
блин
look, I look, I don't know if
нет ну я смотри я я смотри я не знаю ли
you're on the FSB's booths, but logic says the
тебя на буты ФСБ но логика говорит об
opposite, I do
обратном
n't understand why the FSB is here at all,
я не понимаю почему здесь ФСБ вообще и
or the Investigative Committee, I don't know who's
или следственный комитет я не знаю к кто
doing this, on the booths,
у вас занимается этим на буты
and what did I say that was so simple that
а что что я сказал такого что просто что
I can get in, I don't know either, the question is, I
я могу попасть я тоже не знаю вопрос я
don't understand why you're scaring people, I don't know either, but I don't know either, but I don't know either, I don't
не понимаю почему вы пугаете людей я
know your legislation, but logic
знаю я не знаю законодательство ваше но
tells me, yeah, logic, logic tells me, that's how
подсказывает вот так
you think it is, that is, how
вы думаете это вот так оно есть то есть
Russia works, I'm in a
как бы Россия-то так работает
hurry to congratulate you, it doesn't work that way,
всё спешу вас содарщить это так не
okay, okay,
ладно хорошо давай
nice  was to talk
ладно приятно было пообщаться до
goodbye
свидания
[laugh] the
[смех]
type already swam like that
тип аж поплыв
no well maybe maybe not
такий не ну может быть может не
you Father Androni I just took this
вы отец Андрони просто я так взял это
very important moment in your life from the
очень важный момент в твоей жизни от
fact that you
того что ты
say like subscribe comment and share
скажешь лайк подписка комент и розкиньте
this video with your friends subscribe to my
це видео друзям підпишись на мій
Telegram right now axis vin and
Telegram прям зараз ось він а
priest even more and more politely youtube
попик це дуже и дуже важливо youtube
drive us through the karger to  shadowy ban
заганяе нас через каргер в тіньовий бан
and even a lot of videos are not shown to people,
и дуже багато відео не показуется людям
information about streams is often not shown in
вчасно не показуется інформація про
order for us to get a
стрими тому для того щоб ми мали
quick connection to subscribe right
оперативный зв'язок підпишиться прям
away and there is a pop there in the telegram okmdeo, there
зараз а попик там в телеграмі окмдео ще
is also the same tsikava and useful information and us
теж є цікава и корисна інформація и мы
I'm to blame for you trimatiyny
повинні з вами тримати постійний
operational link will
оперативный зв'язок незалежно від того
show you about this YouTube glory of
чи покаже вам про цей YouTube слава
Ukraine subscribe
Україні підпишись